Finding Aid for the Palmer Family Papers LSC.0515
UCLA Library Special Collections
Palmer Family papers
1800-1960
UCLA Library Special Collections
Palmer family
LSC.0515
23.5 Linear Feet (47 boxes and 11 oversize boxes.)
Henry Austin Palmer came to California in 1862 and was employed in a banking and assay office in Folsom until 1864, and then spent a year in assaying in Michigan Bluff. He became the first cashier of the Union National bank, established in 1877, serving as president from 1882-86, while also serving as vice president and treasurer of the Union Savings Bank. The collection consists of photographs, correspondence, diaries, glass slides, glass plate negatives, ephemera, and memorabilia of the Harold King Palmer family of Los Angeles.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Existence and Location of Copies note for the link to the digitized materials.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942335393606533
Biography
Henry Austin Palmer was born in 1842, a native of Stonington, Connecticut; worked there as an express agent, then a clerk in the U.S. custom house; came to California in 1862 and was employed in a banking and assay office in Folsom until 1864, and then spent a year in assaying in Michigan Bluff; worked as cashier in U.S. Mint at San Francisco, 1865-67; cashier at banking house of Banks & Company until 1869 when he organized and was appointed cashier of the Union Savings Bank of Oakland; became the first cashier of the Union National bank, established in 1877, serving as president from 1882-86, while also serving as vice president and treasurer of the Union Savings Bank; in 1867, he married Jane O. Day; their children were Theodore S., Elizabeth Day, and Harold King Palmer; in 1882, along with C.T. Mills and M.L. Wicks, Palmer incorporated the Pomona Land and Water Company; in 1884 served as vice president, and then president until 1887; also became the owner and incorporator of the Pomona Bank in 1883.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of photographs, correspondence, diaries, glass slides, glass plate negatives, ephemera, and memorabilia of the Harold King Palmer family of Los Angeles. Includes materials of Elizabeth Day Palmer, Henry Austin Palmer, the Beggs and Rex family, and the Hart family. Also includes a photograph album of Elizabeth Day Palmer with photographs taken on a trip to Chile, ca. 1903.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Harold King Palmer (Boxes 1-7).
Palmer family (Boxes 8-17, 21-24, 35-49).
Elizabeth Day Palmer (Boxes 18-20).
Henry Austin Palmer (Boxes 25-30).
Beggs family (Boxes 31-33).
Hart family (Box 34).
Photograph album of Chile (Box 50).
Rex and Beggs family photograph album (Box 51).
Glass plate negatives (Boxes 52-58).
Existence and Location of Copies
Digitized materials are available electronically at https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/f4xbs000zz-89112.
Diaries.; Negatives (photographs).; Photographs.; Palmer, Elizabeth Day -- Archives; Palmer, Harold King -- Archives; Palmer, Henry Austin -- Archives; Rex family -- Archives; Hart family; Beggs family--Archives.; Hart family--Archives.; Beggs family; Palmer family -- Archives
- Harold King Palmer
  - Papers and correspondence. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5)
  - Engineering reports. (Box 6)
  - Notebooks. (Box 7)
- Palmer Family
  - H.K. Palmer correspondence files. (Box 8)
  - H.K. Palmer correspondence. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, bank statements, tax returns Mrs. H.K. Palmer (Dorothy Marie Beggs Palmer) Elizabeth Day Palmer Mrs. H.A. Palmer. (Box 10)
  - Deeds, correspondence, etc. Mrs. H.A. Palmer. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, papers, accounts. (Box 13)
  - Deeds, tax records H.K. Palmer & mother, J.O.D. Palmer. (Box 14)
  - Papers, some correspondence. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous papers. (Box 17)
  - Palmer Family Papers and Diaries. (Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24)
  - Palmer Family Photos, etc. (Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39, Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46, Box 47)
  - Palmer Family Photos and negatives. (Box 48)
  - Photographs., Oversize. (Box 49)
  - Certificates, painting. (Box 49)
- Elizabeth Day Palmer
  - Trips, geneology (of the George Rex family). (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, manuscripts, memorabilia. (Box 19)
  - Papers. (Box 20)
- Henry Austin Palmer
  - Business papers. (Box 25)
  - Ledgers and accounts. (Box 26)
  - Correspondence (mostly to Mrs. H.A. Palmer), papers. (Box 27)
  - Contracts, deeds, diaries, etc. much H.A. Palmer & Pomona Land & Water Company. (Box 28)
  - Bank records, accounts. (Box 29)
  - Papers. (Box 30)
- Beggs Family (Utah)
  - Correspondence and papers. (Box 31, Box 32, Box 33)
- Hart Family
  - Papers. (Box 34)
- Photograph Album of Chile
  - Photograph album of Chile, ca.. By Elizabeth Day Palmer., 1903 (Box 50)
- Rex and Beggs Family Photograph Album
  - Photograph album. Rex and Begg family photographs. (Box 51)
- Glass Negatives
  - Mexico. Negative no.1-10. (Box 52)
  - Guatemala. Negative no.11-23. (Box 52)
  - La Libertad, Nicaragua and Panama. Negative no.24-38. (Box 52)
  - Northern Peru. Negative no.39-43. (Box 52)
  - Callao. Negative no.44-57. (Box 52)
  - Lima. Negative no.58-70. (Box 52)
  - Arica / Iquique. Negative no.71-84. (Box 52)
  - Valparaiso. Negative no.85-93. (Box 52)
  - San Felipe / Los Andes. Negative no.94-101. (Box 52)
  - Santiago area. Negative no.102-108. (Box 52)
  - Santiago area. Negative no.109-116. (Box 53)
  - Constitucion Bay and beach. Negative no.117-127. (Box 53)
  - Chile: Characteristic scenes 1. Negative no.128-141. (Box 53)
  - Constitucion. Negative no.142-149. (Box 53)
  - Concepcion, Talcahuano, Lota. Negative no.150-159. (Box 53)
  - Santiago. Negative no.160-173. (Box 53)
  - Chile: Rivers. Negative no.174-178. (Box 53)
  - Chile: Mines--Valdia. Negative no.179-183. (Box 53)
  - Chillan. Negative no.184-192. (Box 53)
  - Valdia, Corral, Osorno. Negative no.193-202. (Box 53)
  - Temuco, Villarica. Negative no.203-217. (Box 53)
  - Chilean Holidays. Negative no.218-227. (Box 54)
  - Chile: Mountains. Negative no.228-237. (Box 54)
  - Chile: Clouds / Fog. (238-239 transparencies). Negative no.238-249. (Box 54)
  - Chile: Characteristic Scenes 2. Negative no.250-265. (Box 54)
  - California: Sonora to Yosemite. (266-267 transparency). Negative no.266-280. (Box 54)
  - California: Half Dome and Peaks in Yosemite.. Negative no.281-294., 1902 (Box 54)
  - California: Falls and lakes in Yosemite.. (295 transparency). Negative no.295-310., 1902 (Box 54)
  - California: Yosemite, Miscellaneous, Hetch Hetchy, Lake Eleanor.. (311-312. Negative no.311-324., 1912 (Box 54)
  - Mount Hamilton--Creeks. Negative no.325-329. (Box 54)
  - Mount Hamilton--Creeks. Negative no.330-339. (Box 55)
  - Mount Hamilton--Ysabel Creek. Negative no.340-351. (Box 55)
  - Mount Hamilton--Ysabel Canyon. Negative no.352-366. (Box 55)
  - Mount Hamilton--Observatory. Negative no.367-383. (Box 55)
  - Mount Hamilton--Landscapes. Negative no.384-398. (Box 55)
  - Mount Hamilton--Fog and clouds. Negative no.399-417. (Box 55)
  - Berkeley--Houses. Negative no.418-430. (Box 55)
  - Berkeley--Interiors. Negative no.431-442. (Box 55)
  - Berkeley--Landscapes. (443 transparency). Negative no.443-457. (Box 56)
  - Berkeley--Portraits. (473-475 transparencies). Negative no.458-475. (Box 56)
  - San Francisco--Cliff House and beach. Negative no.476-478. (Box 56)
  - San Francisco Bay. Negative no.479-492. (Box 49)
  - San Francisco--after the fire.. Negative no.493-511., May 6, 1906 (Box 56)
  - Marin County. Negative no.512-522. (Box 56)
  - Santa Cruz.. Negative no.523-538., August 1900 (Box 56)
  - Claremont.. Negative no.539-552., 1899-1900 (Box 56)
  - Claremont.. Negative no.553-554., 1899-1900 (Box 57)
  - Claremont.. Negative no.555-568., 1900-1901 (Box 57)
  - Salt Lake--Uintah Railroad. Negative no.569-581. (Box 57)
  - Fort Duchesne--Uintah Railroad. Negative no.582-589. (Box 57)
  - Camp views. Negative no.590-603. (Box 57)
  - Red Cap Ditch. Negative no.604-619. (Box 57)
  - Trees. Negative no.620-632. (Box 57)
  - Mountains. Negative no.633-649. (Box 57)
  - Native Americans. Negative no.650-656. (Box 57)
  - Groups. Negative no.657-662. (Box 57)
  - Observatory--Mount Hamilton (?). Negative no.663-664. (Box 57)
  - Views. Negative no.665-671. (Box 58)
  - Irrigation. Negative no.672-685. (Box 58)
  - Irrigation Works. Negative no.686-706. (Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous. Negative no.707-724. (Box 58)
  - Expedition to countryside. Negative no.725-741. (Box 58)
  - Rivers, waterfalls and the sea. Negative no.742-752. (Box 58)
  - Oil wells. Negative no.753-761. (Box 58)
  - Unidentified port. Negative no.762-762. (Box 58)
  - Lake Eleanor (transparency). Negative no.763-763. (Box 58)
  - Yosemite: Half Dome (transparencies). Negative no.764-765. (Box 58)
  - Mirror Lake (transparency). Negative no.766-766. (Box 58)
  - Country lane (transparency). Negative no.767-767. (Box 58)
  - Tahquitz Canyon and Torres Martinez Indian Reservation. Negative no.768-784., 6.5 × 8.5 plates. (Box 58)
  - European views. Negative no.785-790., 5 × 7 plates. (Box 58)
  - Ostend Fish Market. Negative no.791-792., 5 × 7 plates. (Box 58)